SARAH WHEELER

Longmont, CO 80504 720-936-4772

sarah@wheeler.group

www.linkedin.com/in/sarah-wheeler-098615284

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Senior Front-End Web Developer with more than 13 years of experience, almost exclusively in the financial services advertising space. Picks up new programming languages quickly, and takes pride in writing clean, well-organized code. Along with a wealth of experience with Javascript, HTML, and CSS development, is proficient in many Adobe Suite programs and other design tools. Has experience with Vue and React and the libraries associated with those languages, such as NodeJS, Vuetify, Vuex, and Remotion.

SKILLS HTML5 Mastery Full-Stack Development

API Integration Agile Workflow
Advanced CSS Adobe Creative Suite
Frontend Frameworks Responsive design

Expert JavaScript Figma

WORK HISTORY

Senior Web Developer • S&P Global (acquired IHS Markit in March 2022)

Boulder, CO · March 2022 to Current

- Developed data-driven advertising campaigns for financial service companies.
- Worked on Vue- and React-based internal tool applications and websites.
- Created data-driven animated videos in Remotion.

Senior Web Developer • IHS Markit (merged with Markit in July 2016)

Boulder, CO • July 2016 to February 2022

- Developed ad campaign content for more than 30 different clients in the financial services sector.
- Led an initiative to uplift the front end of our advertising services platform, which
 was originally written in Python, to Vue, while also redesigning it to conform to
 modern web design standards.

Web Developer • Markit (merged with Wall Street On Demand in Jan 2013)

Boulder, CO • January 2013 to July 2016

 As senior developer within the advertising services team, created data-driven ad campaigns, landing page experiences, and multi-page marketing sites for multiple financial services clients, including Scottrade, E*Trade, and TD Ameritrade.

Junior Web Developer • Wall Street On Demand

Boulder, CO • August 2010 to December 2012

- Created HTML-based, data-driven advertising content for financial service clients.
- Assisted in development and QA on HTML-based ASP Classic and ASP.NET client websites.

EDUCATION

Master of Arts - Digital Media Studies • University of Denver

Denver, CO • May 2008

Bachelor of Science - Mathematics and Computer Science • *Colorado School of Mines* Golden, CO • December 2005